sierra.com 2018-06-28

# Activision | Privacy Policy

**Activision uses "Cookies" to tailor content and marketing, and to improve and adjust user experiences. To find out more about "Cookies", and the options available to manage them, pleaseclick here. By using this Activision online property, you consent to our use of "Cookies".**

**Welcome to Activision's Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 25, 2018.**

Every day, millions of people worldwide use and enjoy Activision websites, products and services. We appreciate your trust in our products and services. In order to provide you with great games and make them better, Activision Publishing, Inc. (" **Activision** ") will collect both personal information and non-personal information (collectively, " **Information** ") and act as the data controller regarding your personal information. We take care of how your Information is processed and used.

This Privacy Policy:

  * explains how Activision collects, stores, uses, and transfers or discloses your Information **;**
  * applies to all Activision websites, products and services (" **Properties** ") **.**

Activision uses cookies and/or similar technologies on the Properties. For more information about Activision’s use of cookies please see our _Cookie Policy_ , which is also incorporated by reference into this Privacy Policy and made part of this Privacy Policy. 

Activision reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a modified version online at <https://www.activision.com/legal/privacy-policy>, so please review it frequently to ensure you are aware of any changes. If Activision makes a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will provide notice to you in our Privacy Policy as posted and on the Activision home page.

**Table of Contents**

  * **1\. Scope of Activision Privacy Policy**
  * **2\. ESRB Privacy Certified Program**
  * **3\. Information We Collect and How We Use It**
  * **4\. Children and Parents**
  * **5\. Your Choices**
  * **6\. Sharing Information**
  * **7\. Security**
  * **8\. Accessing Information and Retention Period**
  * **9\. Contacting Us**
  * **10\. Important Notice**
  * **11\. Your California Privacy Rights**
  * **12\. Users in the EEA**
  * **13\. Disclosure to Users Outside the US and the EEA**

**1\. Scope of Activision Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy applies to all Properties, including:

  * Activision websites, online products and services;
  * Activision console games; and
  * Activision mobile applications.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to third party websites, online properties, or systems to which our Properties may link or through which our Properties may be accessed, and you accept Activision is not responsible for the security or privacy practices of any such third party websites, properties or systems. In some instances, we may direct you to a site that is operated by a vendor or partner. Even though the page where you provide information may have the look and feel of the Properties, a different privacy policy may govern that information collection by our vendor or partner.

This Privacy Policy does not cover Information provided when you apply for a job at Activision. Please refer [here](https://www.activision.com/legal/applicant-privacy-policy) for more information.

Back to top

**2\. ESRB Privacy Certified Program**  
This Privacy Policy and the ESRB certification seals shown on our Properties confirm that Activision is a valid licensee and participating member in the [Entertainment Software Rating Board's Privacy Certified Program](http://www.esrb.org/privacy/faq.aspx#10) (“ **ESRB Privacy Certified** ”). To protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative and ESRB Privacy Certified has reviewed and certified that we meet established online information collection and use practices on all Activision Properties where this Privacy Policy is posted.

Click here for details Hide details

As part of the ESRB Privacy Certified Program, we are subject to frequent audits of our Properties and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by the ESRB Privacy Certified.

Whenever you visit Properties that display the ESRB Privacy Certified certification seal, you may request information about:

  * Whether a company uses cookies, tracks IP addresses or uses other passive means to collect information;
  * Who, if anyone, is collecting your personal information and how will it be used;
  * With whom, if anyone, will your personal information be shared;
  * What choices you have with regard to the use of your personal information;
  * How you can access and, if necessary, change the personal information a company collects and maintains;
  * Whether and how information is collected from children under 13;
  * How a company ensures data security, quality, and integrity;
  * Where and how to ask questions or file complaints.

_DISCLAIMER: Although ESRB Privacy Certified does not monitor non-English Activision Properties, Activision makes all best efforts to ensure that non-English Properties adhere to applicable data collection guidance and principles set forth by ESRB Privacy Certified, including adherence to EU and other territorial regulations outside of the U.S._

If you believe that we have not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact the ESRB Privacy Certified at: <http://www.esrb.org/privacy/contact.aspx>; or

ESRB  
Attn: Privacy Certified Program  
420 Lexington Ave, Suite 2240  
New York, NY 10170  
_[privacy@esrb.org](mailto:privacy@esrb.org)_

Back to top

**3\. Information We Collect and How We Use It**

Activision collects Information about you from you and other sources. As set out below in more detail, we use and in specific cases may combine that Information to operate, tailor content, personalize, adjust and improve our Properties, and to send you messages or personalized information about our games, your scores, new features and more, including for marketing and promotional purposes.

Click here for details Hide details

**Information Provided By You**  
As set out in more detail in the following, Activision may collect Information from you when you: (A) create an Activision account with a Property; (B) use our Properties; (C) participate in sweepstakes, contests and promotions; (D) use Activision customer service; (E) choose to receive newsletters on products and services, receive marketing emails, and/or participate in surveys; (F) buy Activision services or products online; or (G) allow sharing through Social Media.

**A. Creation of an Activision Account  
**Activision Activision will collect certain Information from you when you register with a Property. Personal information collected during registration includes your first and last name, email address, username, and in specific cases, phone number. This personal information is combined with other Information such as your date of birth, country and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs and services and marketing preferences. Additionally, we collect and combine Information when you link a third party account (e.g., XBOX Live, PlayStation Network, Steam and Battle.net) to your Activision account, such as the username associated with you third party account, and the use of certain Properties may require you to link a third party account to your Activision account. 

**B. Use of Our Properties  
**When you visit or use our Properties we collect, process and/or combine Information about your use of those Properties, such as websites you visited before and after you used a Property, browser type and language, IP address, hardware and software information, advertising ID, third party account information (e.g., the username associated with your XBOX Live, PlayStation Network, Steam or Battle.net account), gameplay data, purchase histories, and Social Media data. We use Cookies and/or similar technologies (collectively referred to as “ **Cookies** ”) to do this.  In addition, we or our partners also use Cookies to serve ads in our Properties. Please see our _Cookie Policy_ for more details.

Activision collects, processes, and combines data such as your age, gender, interests, name, email address, gameplay, marketing preferences, customer service, and device-related information.

Activision also publicly displays certain Information about you, including third party account information and gameplay information, on the Properties. For example, your PlayStation username will be displayed on leaderboards if you are a top player in a certain Activision game, regardless of whether or not you have an Activision account. If you have synced a third party account with your Activision account, we may make your username available to be searched by other users if you have not opted out of this feature. You may unlink the third party account or prevent it from being searched at any time through your Activision profile settings.    

To provide fair gaming experience to all players, Activision uses anti-fraud technologies to prevent any cheating and bad behavior in our games.

**C. Sweepstakes, Contests, and Promotions**

When Activision runs contests or promotions on our Properties, we collect certain Information from participants such as their name, address, postal code, email address, phone number, age and/or date of birth, or other information or content submitted by you. We may also need to collect additional information in order for you to claim a prize. That Information will be combined with other account information and will be used and shared in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**D. Interact with Customer Service**

In order to be able to provide you with customer service and assist you with resolving any issues you may have, Activision collects Information from you including your contact details, together with details of your customer service issue and its resolution.

**E.  Receive Newsletters on Products and Services, Receive Marketing Emails, and/or Surveys**

Activision offers you the ability to receive newsletters or marketing periodically by email about our products and services. We also, from time to time, will send you surveys in order to improve player experience with our games. At any time, you can manage your preferences from your account settings and stop receiving further newsletters by unsubscribing from the link in the footer of each email we send to you. 

**F.  Buy Activision Products or Services Online**

Activision does not collect any credit card and/or billing information when you purchase products or services (such as digital content) online. However, you may be required to provide credit card and/or billing information to one of our third-party vendors in order to complete a purchase. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of our third-party vendors before providing them with your personal information, as their privacy practices may vary from ours. At the time of purchase, in specific cases, you also have the option to provide Information (such as your email address) to Activision for the purpose of sending you additional information or offers.

**G. Social Media**

You can interact with some Properties through social networking sites, such as Facebook and Twitter (or social media plug-ins and applications) (" **Social Media** "). When you interact with Activision and/or the Properties through Social Media you acknowledge that we access your Information, solely in accordance with your Social Media privacy settings, and use it to tailor content, marketing, and improve and adjust user experience relating to Activision Properties, as well as (1) give you exclusive content; (2) personalize your online experience with us within and outside our Properties; and (3) contact you in accordance with applicable marketing preferences through Social Media, including through providing tailored marketing, or directly by sending you the latest news, special offerings, and rewards.

When you post personal information publicly through the Properties, or on Social Media, it will be viewable by other users of these sites and we cannot prevent further use of the personal information by third parties. For more information about how your Social Media uses and protects your personal information, please refer to their privacy policies and terms of use.

**Information Provided By Other Sources**  
We may also obtain Information, such as contact details (for example, name and email address), country, IP address, purchase histories, marketing preferences, cookie information, hardware and software information and other technical information about you from other sources, such as our affiliates, Social Media, our vendors (for example, event ticket providers and merchandise vendors), or partners (for example, advertisers, media partners or platform providers (e.g., Microsoft, Sony, Nintendo and Steam), and combine that Information with Information we have collected from or about you. We only collect Information from other sources where they have confirmed to us they are legally entitled to share it with us.

We use Cookies to provide and support our Properties and each of the uses outlined and described above. Please see our _Cookie Policy_ for more information.

Back to top

**4\. Children and Parents**

Activision does not knowingly collect or store any personal information from children under 13 in the US or under the relevant age threshold in other jurisdictions where the child is located. However, we may collect technical information required for delivering the service and for the support of our internal operations from all users of our Properties. If parents believe that we have unintentionally collected their children’s other personal information or otherwise used their children’s personal information for another purpose, they may reach out to us via the  **Contacting Us**  section below.

We recognize a special need to protect the personal information of children. We urge parents to instruct their children to never give out their real names, addresses, phone numbers, or other personal information without parental permission, when online. Activision also recommends that parents familiarize themselves with parental controls available on consoles, mobile telephones, tablets and other devices they provide to their child and accompany their child if aged under 13 years of age when online. Parents should contact Activision immediately if they have any concerns. Please see the  **Contacting Us**  section below for further details.

Back to top

**5.  Your Choices**

You have choices over the Information provided by you and by other sources, and how that Information is used by Activision. You can exercise your choices by updating your preferences at any time and also by managing your settings on your devices and third party accounts.

Click here for details Hide details

**Your Choices About Information Provided by You**

If you do not want to provide Activision with personal information, then you can choose not to provide it. Please note that if you choose not to provide us with personal information, we may not always be able to provide you with the relevant Activision product or service that you want. For example, without providing an email address, you will not be able to create an Activision account. ****

**Your Choices About Information Provided by Third Parties**

You may be able to control how third parties collect and share your Information by changing your preferences or opting out of collection directly with those third parties. Before disclosing Information to third parties, we recommend you check their respective privacy policies for further details.

**Your Choices About Activision Using Your Information**

You can exercise choices over how Activision uses your personal information and update your preferences at any time:

  * to remove yourself from individual contests or promotions, or from receiving email marketing or newsletters from Activision, simply click the unsubscribe link in the email or access your account from  _<https://www.activision.com/>_  and edit your email marketing preferences. You will need your password to access your account;
  * to disable selected Cookies from collecting information relating to the effectiveness of advertising campaigns or analytics data and from serving you with personalized advertising on our Properties or third party properties please see our Cookie Policy.

If you opt-out of receiving email marketing communications from us, please note we may still contact you occasionally about the status of your account, such as to inform you that your account may be expiring, or for other service related information.

If you are a user located in the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”) and would like to know more about your rights in connection with your personal information, please see the  **** **Users in the EEA** section below.

Back to top

**6\. Sharing Information**

As set out below in more detail, Activision shares Information:

  * with the various Activision group companies for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy;
  * with vendors and partners engaged by Activision in order to provide you with goods or services you have requested or online advertising selected by us;
  * if required to do so by applicable law, regulation or legal process;
  * if necessary to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights;
  * if necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of any person; and
  * in connection with the sale of our business or assets.

Please note that any information, including personal information that you reveal in a bulletin board, message board, chat room or other public forum is publicly viewable.

Click here for details Hide details

**Vendors and Partners**  
Vendors and partners provide goods and services (for example, platform providers, media partners, event ticket providers, merchandise vendors, survey providers, billing, consumer services support, consultancy, information technology hardware and software) to Activision in order to support, operate and develop the Properties and to deliver marketing communications on our behalf. Vendors use your Information to execute, deliver and/or from time to time improve the services they provide. We do not share Information with vendors to use for their own direct marketing purposes or any other purpose other than those set out in this section without your consent.

**Law**  
We will disclose your Information in the good faith belief that we are required to do so by law, including but not limited to disclosure to law enforcement or other government officials in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose you or us to legal liability. 

This may include responding to legal requests from jurisdictions outside of the United States where we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law in that jurisdiction, affects users in that jurisdiction, and is consistent with internationally recognized standards.

**Legal Rights  
**We will disclose your Information where necessary for the purpose of exercising, establishing or defending our legal rights.  For example, we will review your gameplay, communications, and other account information in order to investigate allegations of cheating, hacking or any other breach or alleged breach of any applicable Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy and disclose your personal information, including communications, to our legal advisors, consultants and law enforcement or other government officials.

**Protecting Others  
**We disclose your Information with third parties where we believe this is necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of any person. For example, we disclose Information relating to an online account if we in good faith believe the user of that account is using it in ways that are harmful to others (e.g. making inappropriate contact with minors).

**Sale of Our Business or Assets**  
Separately, in the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, bankruptcy, or other similar event, Activision's customer information including Information and communications may be transferred to our successor or assign.

Back to top

**7\. Security**

Activision takes a range of security measures - as set out in detail below – designed to help protect your Information. However, complete online and offline security  can never be guaranteed, so you should always take care when sharing your information online.

Click here for details Hide details

Activision takes a range of security measures designed to protect your personal information and keep it confidential (unless it is non-confidential by nature, for example, publicly-available information like user generated content, leaderboard rankings, and scores, etc.). We also take steps to ensure that the personal information collected is protected from misuse and alteration. In addition, we request vendors who process personal information on our behalf to themselves take a range of security measures designed to help protect your personal information. However, the Internet by its nature is not a secure environment and the nature of security risks is constantly evolving, as are the technical and organizational industry standards relating to management of those risks. The complete security of any personal information collected, stored or used by us or our vendors cannot therefore be guaranteed.

Back to top

**8\. Accessing Information and Retention Period**

As set out in more detail below, you can view, correct, update, or request the deletion of your personal information in any of your Activision accounts at any time.

Click here for details Hide details

If for any reason you wish to view, correct, or update personal information collected about you, or if you want to deactivate your Activision account, simply access your Activision account through[ https://www.activision.com/](https://www.activision.com/) or another product or service as applicable and edit your personal information. You will need your password to access your personal account. You may also send us an email asking us to deactivate your account at [privacy@activision.com](mailto:privacy@activision.com).

If for any reason you are concerned with the way we are using your personal information, or would like to correct or request that we delete such personal information, you can send your request to us using the contact details set out in the  **Contacting Us**  section below.

**Retention Period**

We delete your personal information which we process for the performance of the contract or based on your consent in case you terminate your contract with us, deactivate your Activision account, withdraw your consent or where you request us to delete your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. As an exception, we will not delete your personal information where we still have a legitimate interest to use your personal information. For example, we may still retain your Information to resolve disputes, enforce our Terms of Use or other user agreements, or comply with legal requirements; in this case, your personal information will be blocked from use for any other purpose. In any case, we will not retain or use your personal information longer than necessary for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. Due to technical reasons, residual copies of Information that has been removed from your account and/or the Properties may remain in our backup systems for approximately one month.

Back to top

**9\. Contacting Us**  
To contact us, you can send us an email  email at [privacy@activision.com](mailto:privacy@activision.com), or write to us at: Activision Publishing, Inc., 3100 Ocean Park Boulevard, Santa Monica, CA 90405, ATTN: Privacy Team/Privacy Policy, or call Privacy Team/Privacy Policy, ph. +1 310 255 2000. For visitors from the EEA, you may also contact our Data Protection Officer by email at DPO@activision.com.

You may also contact ESRB Privacy Certified if you have a question or complaint that has not been resolved to your satisfaction. Please see the  **ESRB Privacy Certified Program**  section at the top of this Privacy Policy for further details.

Back to top

**10\. Important Notice**  
For privacy related information applicable to users who are California residents or based outside the US please see below.

Please note your use of this Activision website, product or service is also subject to the terms of the Activision End User License Agreement available [here](https://support.activision.com/license) and Terms of Use available here.

Back to top

**11\. Your California Privacy Rights**  
Since 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We do not share our customer's personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. For inquiries regarding our disclosure policy, please send us an email to [privacy@activision.com](mailto:privacy@activision.com), or write us at: Activision Publishing, Inc., 3100 Ocean Park Boulevard, Santa Monica, CA 90405 USA, ATTN: Privacy Team/Privacy Policy. We will be happy to honor your request.

**California Privacy Rights for Minor Users**  
Since January 1, 2015, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you, if you are a California resident under the age of 18, to view, correct, or remove Information provided by you or publicly posted by you, by accessing your Activision account through <https://www.activision.com/> or another product or service as applicable and editing/removing your Information. You will need your password to access your personal account. You may also send us an email asking us to remove certain posted content at [privacy@activision.com](mailto:privacy@activision.com). In the alternative, you may write to us at Activision Publishing, Inc., 3100 Ocean Park Boulevard, Santa Monica, CA 90405 USA, ATTN: Privacy Team/Privacy Policy.

We will be happy to review, update or remove Information and/or content as appropriate. Residual copies of Information and/or content that have been removed from your account and/or the Properties may remain in our backup systems for approximately one month. We may still retain your Information to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreement, or comply with legal requirements; in this case, your personal information will be blocked from use for any other purpose.

**Do Not Track**

California Business and Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January 1, 2014) permits our customers who are California residents to be informed as to how Activision responds to Web browser "Do Not Track" settings. As Do Not Track is a standard that is currently being developed, Activision does not take actions to respond to Do Not Track settings, and instead we adhere to the standards set out in this Privacy Policy.  

If you would like to find out more about Do Not Track you may find the following link useful: <http://www.allaboutdnt.com/>.

Back to top

**12\. Users in the EEA**

As set out in more detail below, we only process or transfer your personal information where we can rely on legal grounds and appropriate safeguards to do so. You also have additional rights regarding your personal information if you are located in the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”). 

Click here for details Hide details

**Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Information**

We only process your personal information where we can rely on legal grounds to do so. We process your personal information for the purposes set out below.

_Performance of the Services_

We process your personal information for the performance of our services, to provide or support of our products, or for any other feature you request or enable. This includes, for example, using your personal information to:

  * administer your Activision Account;
  * provide contests or promotions in which you have enrolled;
  * support purchases you make;
  * support game functionality;
  * provide global customer service; or
  * provide a fair gaming experience by using anti-fraud technologies such as bans or blocks of accounts.

_Consent_

We process your personal information based on your consent. This includes, for example, providing:

  * newsletters, direct e-mails and surveys about our Properties; and
  * certain other marketing features.

_Legitimate Interest_

We process your personal information where we have a legitimate interest to do so. This includes, for example, processing:

  * to provide you with requested customer service or technical support;
  * to debug and improve our current and future Properties;
  * in order to give you exclusive content, personalize your online experience with us and contact you in accordance with applicable marketing preferences; and
  * for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims or whenever courts are acting in their judicial capacity.

_Legal Obligation_

We process your personal information for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject.  

**Your Rights to Your Personal Information**

You have the following rights in addition to your rights to view, correct, update, or request the deletion of your personal information as set out in detail in the ******Accessing Information**  section above. To access or delete your personal information, you can also make a request [here](https://support.activision.com/gdpr?uil=en).

You may object to the processing of your personal information based on a legitimate interest on grounds relating to your particular situation. You may, in particular, control the extent to which we market to you and you have the right to request that we stop sending you marketing messages at any time. You can use the methods described in the **Accessing Information **section above.

In certain circumstances, you can request that we transfer personal information that you have provided to us. You can send your request to us ___[here](https://support.activision.com/gdpr?uil=en)_.

Where we rely on your consent in order to process your personal information, you have the right to withdraw such consent to further use of your personal information at any time. You can use the methods described in the **Accessing Information **section above to update your marketing preferences.

For each of the rights described above, you can also send your request to us by using the contact details set out in the ******Contacting Us**  section above

We hope that we can satisfy queries you may have about the way we process your personal information. However, if you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to complain to data protection authorities. You can bring the complaint in your member state of residence, place of work or where an alleged infringement of data protection law occurred.

**International Transfers**

Your personal information will be transferred to and processed in the United States where many of our central databases operate or other countries where Activision group companies or vendors maintain facilities or business operations. We use European Commission approved contract clauses to protect your personal information. If you have questions, please contact us using the contact details set out in the **Contacting Us** section above.

Back to top

**13\. Disclosure to Users Outside the US and the EEA**

In addition, if you are a visitor to our websites or other online products and services from outside the U.S., the personal information you provide will be collected, processed and stored directly on, or transferred to, servers in the United States or other countries where Activision group companies or our other partners or vendors maintain facilities or business operations.

No matter where the Information is located, Activision takes commercially reasonable measures to safeguard your privacy rights in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the collection, processing, storage and transfer of your Information, please do not provide your Information when requested and stop using our websites and other online products and services.

Unfortunately, as of September 1st, 2015, we no longer offer Activision accounts to Russian based consumers.

Back to top
